<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Sur-rejoinder of Mr. Attorney General to the rejoinder made on the behalf of the charter of the city of London</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Attorney-General (1681-1687 : Sawyer)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1682</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 34 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A61989</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S6195</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R769</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11945025</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11945025</idno>
            <idno type="VID">51315</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A61989)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 51315)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 516:12)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Sur-rejoinder of Mr. Attorney General to the rejoinder made on the behalf of the charter of the city of London</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Attorney-General (1681-1687 : Sawyer)</author>
                  <author>Sawyer, Robert, Sir, 1633-1692.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 11 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for S. Mearne,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1682.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>London (England) --  Charters, grants, privileges.</term>
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <div xml:lang="eng" type="version">
               <pb facs="tcp:51315:1"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:51315:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <p>THE SUR-REJOINDER OF <hi>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Attorney General</hi> TO THE REJOINDER Made on the behalf of the CHARTER Of the CITY of LONDON.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>LONDON</hi> Printed for <hi>S. Mearne,</hi> 1682.</p>
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:51315:2"/>
               <p>
                  <gap reason="missing" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page missing〉</desc>
                  </gap>City aforeſaid, as to the making and publiſhing of the Law for the levy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of monies of the perſons coming to the publick Markets held within the ſaid City with Victuals and Proviſions there to be ſold, and the exacting and levying of ſuch monies above ſuppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed to be made by them the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens above, by rejoining, pleaded for our ſaid Lord the King that now is, ſays, that for a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny thing by them therein alledged the Liberties, Priviledges, and Franchiſes, to be of themſelves one Body Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate and Politick in Matter, Fact, and Name, by the name of the Mayor and Commonalty, and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and by the ſame name to plead and be impleaded, to anſwer and to be anſwered by them above as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid claimed, ought not to be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed to the ſaid Mayor and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens, becauſe that by proteſting that they the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty &amp; Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> the aforeſaid ſeventeenth day of <hi>September</hi> in the ſix and twentieth year aboveſaid in the aforeſaid Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plication mentioned, as alſo continually afterwards and from the time whereof the memory of man is not to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, were not ſeized, or as yet are ſeized of, and in the publick Markets aforeſaid in their Demeſne as of Fee, nor by the whole time aforeſaid at their own charges, have provided, or have been accuſtomed, or ought to provide Market-places, or places where ſuch Markets were to be held, as often as need ſhould be, and Stalls, Standings, and other conveniences for perſons coming to the ſaid Markets with Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctuals and Proviſions there to be ſold, for the better and more convenient ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſing of the ſame to ſale, as the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens above by rejoining have alledged, and proteſting alſo that the aforeſaid Rates by the Act or Ordinance afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:51315:2"/>ſo as aboveſaid, ordered to be paid at the aforeſaid time of the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of that Order, and from thence hitherto were not reaſonable, nor as yet are reaſonable, as they the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens have likewiſe above alledged. Not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding for Plea, the ſaid Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney General of our ſaid Lord the now King, ſays, that by a certain Act in Parliament of our ſaid Lord the now King, held at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> by ſeveral Prorogations the Fourteenth day of <hi>February,</hi> in the Two and twentieth Year of the Reign of our ſaid Lord the now King (amongſt other things) it was enacted, to the end that fit and commodious places within the ſaid City and Liberties thereof, might be ſet out and appointed for the rebuil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding and keeping Markets with grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter conveniency than before they had been; ſo that the principal Streets might not be peſtered and obſtructed thereby as before they had been accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomed, and that the Royal Exchange, Guild-hall, the Seſſions Houſe in the Old-baily and the common Goals and Priſons within the ſaid City might be enlarged and made more commodious for the publick uſe and ornament of the City, and be better ſecured from the danger and caſualty of Fire; and that ſome convenient diſtance, interval, and circuit of ground might be left be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the Royal Exchange, and other Houſes to be built within the ſaid Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty. That the Mayor, Aldermen, and Commons of the ſaid City, in Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-Council aſſembled, ſhould and might imploy, and by the aforeſaid Act they were authorized to imploy ſuch places and portions of Ground within the ſaid City and Liberties thereof, as by and with the approbation of our ſaid Lord the King, then were, or before the tenth day of <hi>March</hi> 1669. ſhould be ſet out and adjudged neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ary and convenient, as well for the
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:51315:3"/>publick Market-places there, as alſo for the ornament, enlargement, and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veniency of the ſaid Royal Exchange, and other places before mentioned, and every, or any of them reſpective<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly; And to the intent that a reaſona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble ſatisfaction might be given to the Proprietors, and others, having any Eſtate or Intereſt in the grounds and places which had been, or ſhould be ſet out, taken, and uſed for publick Market-places; the aforeſaid Mayor, Aldermen, and Commons, by them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, or others in that behalf to be appointed and authorized, were to treat, and agree with the Owners, and others intereſſed in the ſame: and in caſe of a wilful refuſal, or of any ſuch diſability or impediment, as in a certain other Act of Parliament, in the ſaid Act ſpecified for the rebuilding of the City of <hi>London</hi> (lately before made) were mentioned, or of any other in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>capacity whatſoever in the Owners thereof, or others intereſſed in the ſame, to treat and agree. The ſaid Mayor and Court of Aldermen ſhould, and were by the foreſaid Act authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zed and required to cauſe Juries to be impannelled in ſuch manner and form as by the aforeſaid Act it was directed and appointed, ſo as no two Jurors ſo to be impannelled, ſhould come out of one and the ſame Ward to adjudge and aſſeſs what recompence and ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faction in every of the Caſes aforeſaid ought to be awarded and given to the reſpective Owners, and others intereſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fed in the Grounds and Places ſo ſet out, to be taken and imployed for any the uſes or purpoſes as aforeſaid, in purſuance of the ſaid Act, according to ſuch their reſpective Eſtates and Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſts. And it was further Enacted, that for all ſorts of Coals which from and after the firſt day of <hi>May,</hi> One thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand ſix hundred and ſeventy, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Nine and twentieth day of <hi>September,</hi> which ſhould be in the Year
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:51315:3"/>of our Lord, One thouſand ſix hundred eighty ſeven, ſhould be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported and brought into the ſaid Port of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or the River of <hi>Thames</hi> within the Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties of the ſaid City, upon the ſame River, there ſhould be paid by way of Impoſition thereupon, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the Rates hereafter mentio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned (that is to ſay) for all ſuch Coals as ſhould be there imported and brought in from and after the ſaid firſt day of <hi>May,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred and ſeventy, and before the Four and twentieth day of <hi>June,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venty ſeven, there ſhould be paid for every Chaldron or Tun thereof, two ſhillings over and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove the Impoſition of twelve pence the Chaldron or Tun, by the ſaid Act for the Rebuilding the City of <hi>London</hi> appointed to be paid. And for all ſuch Coals which ſhould be there imported, and brought in, from and after the ſaid Four and twentieth day of <hi>June,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ſeventy ſeven, and before the ſaid Nine and twentieth day of <hi>September,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred and eighty ſeven, there ſhould be paid for every Chaldron or Tun there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of three ſhillings, and the ſame ſhould by virtue of the ſaid Act be collected, levyed, and paid in ſuch ſort and manner, in all and every reſpect, as in and by the ſaid former Act was limitted and appointed for the collecting and levying the duty of twelve pence the Chaldron or Tun of Coals impoſed by the ſaid former Act, and all and every the Powers, Authorities, Directions, and Proviſions, in or by the ſaid former Act mentioned or provided for the levying and collecting there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of; all which monies ſo to be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived upon account of the ſaid
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:51315:4"/>reſpective Impoſitions, or either of them, ſhould from time to time be paid into the Receipt of the Chamber of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and from thence ſhould be iſſued out &amp; paid according to the directions and appointment of the aforeſaid Act of the Two and twentieth year aboveſaid, and not otherwiſe; and the ſaid Chamber of the City of <hi>London</hi> ſhould ſtand and be char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged with all the reſidue of the ſaid monies there paid in, which ſhould not be iſſued out and paid accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dingly. And it was further ena<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted, that all and every ſum and ſumms of money which ſhould be raiſed upon the receipt of the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral and reſpective Impoſitions a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid or by ſuch additional duty in caſe of concealment thereof, as by the aforeſaid former Act was ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, ſhould be imployed and diſpoſed in manner and form fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing, (that is to ſay) one fourth part of all the monies which from and after the ſaid firſt day of <hi>May,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ſeven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, and before the ſaid four and twentieth day of <hi>June,</hi> One thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand ſix hundred ſeventy ſeven, ſhould be raiſed and payable upon the receipt of the aforeſaid Impoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of two ſhillings for every Chal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dron or Tun of Coals, or in caſe of concealment thereof as aforeſaid, ſhould be imployed and diſpoſed of, for and towards the ſatisfaction for the Grounds ſet out and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed for enlarging of the Streets, making of Wharfs and Keys, pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Market Places, and other pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Uſes, as well in that Act as in the Act afore-recited, mentioned, and appointed, and that one moiety of all the monies which from and af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the ſaid Four and twentieth day of <hi>June,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ſeventy ſeven, ſhould be
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:51315:4"/>raiſed or payable upon the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Impoſition of three ſhillings the Chaldron or Tun of Coals from time to time ſhould be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed and diſpoſed for ſatisfacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on for the Ground ſet out and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed as aforeſaid, and for ſuch other publick uſes and purpoſes as in that Act and in the Act before recited, were mentioned and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, as by the ſame Act of the Two and twentieth year above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, amongſt other things more at large is manifeſt', and doth ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear. And the ſaid Attorney Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral of our ſaid Lord the now King, Who, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for our ſaid Lord the now King, further ſays that by virtue of that Act, they the ſaid Major and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, before the making and publiſhing of the aforeſaid Law, (to wit) the firſt day of <hi>September,</hi> in the ſix and twentieth year of the reign of our ſaid Lord the now King aforeſaid, at <hi>London</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, in the Pariſh and Ward a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, had and receivid for Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Tax aforeſaid, of two ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings every Chaldron or Tun of Coals brought into the City of <hi>London,</hi> or the Port thereof, a great ſum of money to the purpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes aforeſaid. And further the ſaid Attorney General of our ſaid Lord the now King, Who, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for our ſaid Lord the now King, ſays that the Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London,</hi> without any right, title, or autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity whatſoever, (the aforeſaid pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes notwithſtanding) the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Thurſday (to wit) the ſaid ſeventeenth day of <hi>September</hi> in the ſix and twentieth year of the reign of our ſaid Lord the now King aforeſaid, and in their Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:51315:5"/>Council then held in the Chamber of the Guild-hall of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, (to wit) in the Pariſh of St. <hi>Michael Baſſiſhaw London,</hi> being aſſembled together, made, eſtabliſhed, and publiſhed the aforeſaid Law by themſelves in fact enacted for the levying the aforeſaid ſeveral ſumms of money of all the Subjects and Liege People of our Lord the now King, as well Free men as not Free men of the City of <hi>London,</hi> and of other Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reigners coming to the ſaid publick Markets held within the ſaid City, with their Victuals and Proviſions there to be ſold, and have raiſed and levied, and have made to be raiſed and levied the ſaid ſeveral ſums of money, under the ſole co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lour and pretence of the Law afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, ſo illegally made by themſelves for their private gain and profit, and without any other right, title, or authority whatſoever, by the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid ſpace of ſeven years (after the ſaid ſeventeenth day of <hi>September</hi> in the ſix and twentieth year a foreſaid) next following and upwards, at <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> aforeſaid, in the Pariſh afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, of all the Liege People and Subjects of our ſaid Lord the King, coming to the ſaid publick Markets (by the whole time aforeſaid) held within the ſaid City, with Victuals and Proviſions, there to be ſold, and converted and diſpoſed of theſe mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies to their own uſes, in ſubverſion of the good Rule and Government of the aforeſaid City, and to the great oppreſſion and impoveriſhing of all the Liege People of our ſaid Lord the now King, reſorting and coming to the ſaid Markets with their Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctuals and Proviſions, to the great damage and hurt of all the Liege People and Subjects of our ſaid
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:51315:5"/>Lord the King, to the increaſing of the Prices of all Victuals and Proviſions ſold in the aforeſaid Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kets, and to the manifeſt diſheriting of our ſaid Lord the now King, and his Royal Crown, and againſt the Truſt in them repoſed (as in a Body Corporate and Politick) by our ſaid Lord the King, and the Laws of this Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> as the ſaid Attorney General of our ſaid Lord the now King, for our ſaid Lord the now King above, by reply<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, hath alledged. Without that that the ſaid Mayor and Commonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Citizens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> from the time whereof the me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mory of man is not to the contrary, have had, or have been accuſtomed to have Tolls, Rates, or Sums of money by them the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City aforeſaid above ſuppoſed to be aſſeſſed by the aforeſaid Law or Ordinance, and reduced to a cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainty, as by the Plea of them the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid above, by rejoyning is ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed; and this the ſaid Attorney General of our ſaid Lord the now King is ready to aver; Whereupon for that the ſaid Major and Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty and Citizens for the cauſe a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, have forfeited the Liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Priviledges, and Franchiſes, to be of themſelves a Body Corporate and Politick; the ſaid Attorney Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral as formerly for our ſaid Lord the King, prayeth Judgment, and that the ſaid Mayor and Commonal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and Citizens of the City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> aforeſaid, may be convicted of the premiſes aforeſaid, and be fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judged and excluded from their Liberties, Priviledges, and Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chiſes. <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And as to the Plea of the afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:51315:6"/>Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City aforeſaid above by rejoining, pleaded as to the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidue of the ſaid Plea of the ſaid Attorney General in aſſigning the Forfeitures as aforeſaid above, by replying pleaded, the ſaid Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney General of our ſaid Lord the now King, proteſting that the ſaid Prorogation of the ſaid Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment by our ſaid Lord the King, was for divers neceſſary and urgent cauſes concerning the good and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit of our ſaid Lord the King and his Kingdom, and according to the true and undoubted Prerogative and power of our ſaid Lord the now King, and by the ſame Proro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gation the proſecution of publick Juſtice of the Kingdom, and the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king neceſſary proviſions for the preſervation of our ſaid Lord the King and his Proteſtant Subjects had not received interruption, as by the aforeſaid Petition by the Votes and Suffrages of the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the ſaid City in their ſaid Com. Council aſſembled ſo as aforeſaid ordained, falſly and maliciouſly is alledged, notwithſtanding for Plea the ſaid Attorney General for our ſaid Lord the now King, ſays that the Plea of the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid above, by rejoining in that behalf pleaded, and the matter therein contained, is not ſufficient in Law for them the Mayor and Com and Citizens of the City afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, to claim the Liberties, Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges and Franchiſes aforeſaid, to be of themſelves a Body Corporate &amp; Politick, in Matter, Fact, and Name, by the name of the Mayor &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, and by the ſame name to plead and be impleaded to
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:51315:6"/>anſwer and be anſwered, to be to them allowed or adjudged, or main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained: And that he the ſaid At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney General (to that! Plea in manner and form aforeſaid plead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed) is not neceſſitated, nor by the Law of the Land bound in any wiſe to anſwer for our ſaid Lord the now King; and this the ſaid Attorney General of our ſaid now Lord the King is ready to aver. Whereupon for want of a ſufficient Plea of them the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City aforeſaid in this behalf, the ſaid Attor. General of our ſaid Lord the now King for our ſaid Lord the now King, as formerly, prays Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and that the ſaid Mayor and Commonalty and Citizens of the City of <hi>London</hi> aforeſaid, may be convicted of the premiſes, and be forejudged and excluded from their Liberties, Priviledges, and Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chiſes.</p>
            </div>
            <div xml:lang="lat" type="version">
               <pb n="2" facs="tcp:51315:2"/>
               <p>
                  <gap reason="missing" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page missing〉</desc>
                  </gap>ctionem &amp; publicationem legis pro levatione denariorum de perſonis ad publica Mercata infra Civitat' prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' tent' cum victualibus &amp; provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſionibus ibidem vendend'acceden' ac exactionem &amp; levationem hujuſmo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>di denar' ſuperius fieri ſuppoſit' per ipſos Majorem &amp; Communit' ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ves ſuperius rejungendo placitat' pro eodem Domino Rege nunc dicit quod per aliqua per ipſos ſuperius inde al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>legat' libertat' privileg' &amp; Francheſ. fore de ſeipſis unum corpus corporat' &amp; politicum in re facto &amp; nomine per nomen Majoris &amp; Communitat' ac Civium Civitat' London ac per idem nomen placitare &amp; implacitari reſpondere ae reſponderi per ipſos ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perius ut prefertur clamat' eiſdem Majori &amp; Communitat' ac Civibus allocari non debent quia proteſtando quod ipſi praedict' Major &amp; Commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nit' ac Cives Civitat' <hi>London</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' decimo ſeptimo die <hi>Septembris,</hi> anno viceſimo ſexto ſupradicto in Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plicatione praedict' mentionat' nec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>non continue poſtea &amp; à tempore cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jus contrar' memoria hominum non exiſtit minime ſeiſit' fuer' ſeu ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>huc ſeiſit' exiſtunt de &amp; in pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licis Mercatis praedict' in domini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>co ſuo ut de feodo, nec per totum idem tempus ſumptibus ſuis propriis pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viderunt ſeu providere conſuever' &amp; debuerunt fora Mercatoria ſive loca ubi hujuſmodi Mercata tent' fuer' quotieſcunque neceſſe fuit &amp; Stallas, Stationes, &amp; alias accommo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dationes pro perſonis ad eadem Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cata venien' cum victualibus &amp; pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſionibus ibidem vendend' pro me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liori &amp; magis convenien' vendicon' expoſicon' eorundem prout praedict' Major &amp; Communitat' ac Cives ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perius rejungendo allegaver' prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtandoque etiam quod Rat' praedict' per actum ſive ordination' praedict' ut praefertur ſolvi ordinat' praedict' tempore confectionis ordinationis il<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lius
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:51315:2"/>&amp; extunc hucuſque non fuer' rationabiles, nec adhuc rationa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>biles exiſtunt, prout iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives ſuperius ſimiliter allegaverunt. Pro placito tamen idem dict' Attorn' dict' Domin' Regis nunc Generalis di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cit quod per quendam actum in Parliamento dict' Dom' Regis nunc tent' apud <hi>Weſtmonaſter'</hi> per ſepera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>les Prorogationes decimo quarto die <hi>Februarii,</hi> Anno Regni dict' Dom' Regis nunc viceſimo ſecundo, inter alia inactitat' fuit ad finem quod apti &amp; commodi loci infra dictam Civitat' &amp; Libertat' ejuſdem, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tra poſit' &amp; appunctuat' forent pro reedificand' &amp; cuſtodiend' Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cata ampliori convenientia quam antea fuer' ita quod principales ſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tae non forent impedit' Anglice pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtred' &amp; obſtruct' perinde prout an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tea conſuet' fuit. Et quod Regale Excambium, Guihald', le Seſſions Houſe in le Old-baily &amp; commun' Gaole &amp; Priſone infra praedict' Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitat' forent amplificat' &amp; fact' magis commodi pro publicis uſu &amp; ornament' Civitatis, &amp; melius ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curitat' à periculo &amp; caſualitate conflagrationis. Et quod alique con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venien' diſtantiae, intervall' &amp; cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuitus fundi forent relict' inter Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gal' Excambium, &amp; alias domos edificand'infra Civitat' praedict' quod Major, Aldermanni, &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mun' Civitat' praedict' in Commun' Concilio aſſemblat' impenderent, An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>glice, <hi>ſhould and might imploy,</hi> &amp; per Actum praedict' Authoritat' fuer' impendere talia loca &amp; por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion' Fundi infra Civitat' praedict' &amp; Libertat' ejuſdem prout per &amp; cum dicti Domini Regis nunc ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>probation' tunc ſuer' vel ante de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cimum diem Martii, Milleſimo Sexcenteſimo Sexageſimo Nono, fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent extrapoſit' &amp; adjudicat' ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſar' &amp; convenien' tam pro pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licis
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:51315:3"/>Mercatis ibidem, quam etiam pro ornamento amplificatione &amp; convenien' praedict' Regal' Excam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bii, &amp; aliorum locorum praementio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nat' &amp; cujuſlibet vel alicujus eo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rundem reſpective &amp; ad intention' quod rationabilis ſatisfactio dat' ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ret Proprietar' &amp; alior' habent' a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liquem ſtatum ſive intereſſe in fun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dis &amp; locis quae fuiſſent vel ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent extrapoſit', capiend', &amp; occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pand' pro publicis locis Mercatoriis praedict' Major, Alderman' &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mun' per ipſos vel alios in ea parte fore appunctuat' &amp; authorizat' tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctarent &amp; agrearent cum Proprietor' &amp; al'intereſſat' in eiſdem &amp; in ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſu voluntarie recuſationis ſive ali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cujus talis inhabilitatis ſive impedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment' qual'in quodam al' Actu Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liamenti in eodem Actu ſpecificat' pro re-edificatione Civitat' <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> nuper antea fact' mentionat' fuer' ſeu alius incapacitat' cujuſcun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>que inde Proprietar' inde vel alias intereſſat' in eiſdem ad tractand' &amp; agreand' praedict' Major &amp; Cur' Alderman' forent &amp; fuer' per A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctum praedict' authorizat' &amp; re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiſit' cauſare Jur' fore impan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nellat' in tal' modo &amp; forma pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ut per Actum praedict' direct' &amp; appunctuat' fuit, ita quod null' duo Jur' praedict' ſic fore impannellat' venirent ex una &amp; eadem Warda adjudicare &amp; aſſidere qual' compen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſation' &amp; ſatisfaction' in quibuſlibet caſibus praedict' forent adjudicat' &amp; dat' reſpectivis Proprietor' &amp; aliis intereſſat' in fundis &amp; locis ſic ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trapoſit' capiend' &amp; occupand' pro aliquibus uſubus vel propoſitis ut prefertur in proſecutione ejuſdent Actus ſecundum tal'eorum reſpecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vos ſtatus &amp; intereſs'. Et ulterius inactitat' fuit quod pro omnimodis Carbonibus quae ab &amp; poſt primum diem <hi>Maii,</hi> Milleſimo Sexcenteſimo &amp; Septuageſimo, &amp; ante viceſimum
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:51315:3"/>nonum diem <hi>Septembris,</hi> qui foret in Anno Dom' Milleſimo Sexcenteſimo Octogeſimo Septimo, forent importat' &amp; abduct' in praedict' Portum Civitat' <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> ſeu Rivum <hi>Thameſis,</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frae Libertat' Civit' praedict' ſuper eundem Rivum ſolut' foret per viam Impoſitionis, ſuperinde ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cund' ratas poſtea mentionat' <hi>(vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>del')</hi> pro omnibus tal' Carbonibus qual ibi importat' &amp; induct' fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent ab &amp; poſt primum diem <hi>Maii,</hi> Milleſimo Sexcenteſimo &amp; Sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuageſimo, &amp; ante viceſimum quartum diem <hi>Junii,</hi> Milleſimo Sexcenteſimo Septuageſimo Septi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mo, ſolut' foret pro qualibet Cel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dar' ſeu Tonna inde duos ſolidos ultra Impoſition' duodecim denar' pro Celdar' ſeu Tonna per praedict' Actum pro re-edificatione Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat' <hi>London,</hi> appunctuat' ſol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vend'. Et pro omnibus tal' Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bonibus quae ibidem importat' &amp; induct' forent ab &amp; poſt praedict' viceſimum quartum diem <hi>Junii,</hi> Milleſimo Sexcenteſimo Septuage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſimo Septimo, &amp; ante praedict' Viceſimum Nonum diem <hi>Sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tembris,</hi> Milleſimo Sexcenteſimo Octogeſimo Septimo, ſolut' forent pro qualibet Celdar' ſive Tonna inde tres ſolides, &amp; iidem Vigore Actus praedict' forent collect' le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vat' &amp; ſolut' in tali forma &amp; modo in omni &amp; quolibet reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctu, prout in &amp; per praedict' prio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rem Actum fuit limitat' &amp; ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>punctuat' pro collectione &amp; leva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tione debit' duodecim denar' pro Celdar' ſive Tonna Carbonum im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſit' per priorem Actum praedict' &amp; omnes &amp; quaſlibet poteſtat' Authoritat', Directiones, &amp; Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſion' in vel per praedict' prio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rem Actum mentionat' vel pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſ. pro levatione &amp; collectione inde. Omneſ<expan>
                     <am>
                        <g ref="char:abque"/>
                     </am>
                     <ex>que</ex>
                  </expan> quidem denar' ſic
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:51315:4"/>recipiend' ſuper comput' praedict' reſpectivarum Impoſition' ſeu ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum alterius de tempore in tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pus forent ſolut' in receptu Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merae Civitat' <hi>London,</hi> &amp; abin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>de forent emanat' &amp; ſolut' ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cundum directionem &amp; appun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctuation' praedict' Actus de An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>no Viceſimo Secundo ſupradicto &amp; non aliter. Et praedict' Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mera Civitat' <hi>London,</hi> ſtaret &amp; onerat' fuit cum toto reſid' de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nar' praedict' ibidem ſolut' qui non ſic emanat' forent &amp; ſolut'. Et ulterius inactitat' fuit quod omnes &amp; quaelibet ſumma &amp; ſum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mae monet' quae levat' foret ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per reception' ſeperal' &amp; reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctivarum Impoſition' praedict' ſive per tal'additional' debit' in caſu concelament' inde prout per prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' priorem Actum appunctuat' fuit foret' occupat' &amp; diſpoſit' mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>do &amp; forma ſequen' <hi>(videl')</hi> una quarta pars omnium denarior' quae ab &amp; poſt praedict' primum diem <hi>Maii,</hi> Milleſimo Sexcente<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſimo &amp; Septuageſimo &amp; ante prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' Viceſimum Quartum diem <hi>Junii,</hi> Milleſimo Sexcenteſimo Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ptuageſimo Septimo forent levat' ſive ſolubil' ſuper reception' prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' Impoſition' duorum ſolid' pro qualibet Celdar' vel Tonna Carbonum ſen in caſu concela<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment' inde ut prefertur foret' occupat' &amp; diſpoſit' pro &amp; erga ſatisfaction' pro fundis extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſit' &amp; occupat' pro amplifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>catione, Stratarum confection' Wharfarum &amp; Portuum pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licorum Mercatorum locorum &amp; aliorum publicum uſuum tam in Actu ill' quam in Actu praecitat' mentionat' &amp; appunctuat' &amp; quod una medietas omnium de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nar' qui ab &amp; poſt Viceſimum quartum diem <hi>Junii,</hi> Milleſimo Sexcenteſimo Septuageſimo Sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>timo
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:51315:4"/>forent levation' ſeu ſolubil', ſuper praed' Impoſit' trium ſolid pro Celdar' vel Tonna Carbo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num de tempore in tempus fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ret, occupat' &amp; diſpoſit' pro ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfactione pro fundo extrapo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſit', &amp; occupat' ut prefertur, &amp; tal'al' publicis uſibus &amp; pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſit' qual'in actu ill' &amp; in A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctu praerecitat' fuer' mentionat' &amp; appunctuat' prout per eundem Actum de anno Viceſimo Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cundo ſupradicto inter al' plenius liquet &amp; apparet. Et praedict' Attorn' dict' Dom' Regis nunc general' qui &amp;c. pro eodem Dom' Rege nunc ulterius dicit quod vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute actus illius iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civitat' <hi>London</hi> praedict', ante confe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctionem &amp; publicationem legis praedict', ſcilicet primo die <hi>Sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tembris,</hi> anno Regni dicti Dom' Regis nunc Viceſimo Sexto ſupra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicto apud <hi>London</hi> praedict' in Parochia &amp; Warda praedict' ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buer' &amp; receper' pro debito &amp; vecligali praedict' de duobus ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lidis pro qualibet Celdar' ſive Tonna Carbonum in Civitat' <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> ſive Portum ejuſdem im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portat' vigint' denariorum ſum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mam ad propoſita praedict'. Et ulterius idem Attorn' dict' Dom' Regis nunc General', qui, &amp;c. pro eodem D. Rege nunc dicit quod Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civitat' <hi>London,</hi> abſque aliquo jure, titulo, ſive authoritat' qui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buſcunque premiſſis praedict' non obſtantibus praedict' die Jovis ſcilicet praedict' Decimo Septi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mo die <hi>Septembris,</hi> anno reg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ni dict' Dom' Regis nunc Vice<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſimo Sexto ſupra dict' in eorum Commun' Concilio adtunc tent' in Camera Guildhall Civitat' <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> praedict', <hi>videlicet,</hi> in Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rochia
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:51315:5"/>Sancti <hi>Michaelis Baſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhaw London,</hi> inſimul aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blat' fecer' condider' &amp; publi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caver' praedict' legem per ipſos de facto inactitat' pro levatio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ne ſeperal' denar' ſummarum praedict' de omnibus Subditis ac Ligeis Domin' Regis nunc tam liberis quam non liberis homi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nibus Civitat' praedict' &amp; aliis extraneis ad publica Mercat' infra Civit' praedict' tent' acce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den' cum Viclual' &amp; Proviſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mbus ſuis ibidem vendend'ac eaſdem ſeperal' denar' ſummas ſub ſolo colore &amp; praetextu legis praedict' ſic per ipſos pro eorum privato lucro &amp; commodo ille<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>galiter fact' &amp; abſque aliquo alio Jure, Titulo, ſive Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat' quibuſeunque per praedict' ſpatium Septem Annorum poſt praedict' Decimum Septimum di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>em <hi>Septembris,</hi> Anno Viceſimo Sexto ſupradicto prox' ſequen' &amp; amplius apud <hi>London</hi> prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict', in Parochia praedict' de omnibus dict' Domin' Regis Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geis &amp; Subditis ad praedict' publica Mercata per totum tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pus praedict' infra Civitat' prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' tent' cum Victual' &amp; Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſionibus ibidem vendend'ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cedentibus exeger' &amp; levaver' &amp; exigi &amp; levari fecer' &amp; denar' ill'ad eorum proprios uſus converterunt &amp; diſpoſue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>runt in ſubverſion' boni regimi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nis &amp; Gubernation' Civitatis praedict' &amp; in magnam oppreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſien' &amp; depauperation' omnium dicti Domini Regis nunc Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>georum ad Mercata praedict' cum Victualibus &amp; proviſionibus ſuis acceden' &amp; venien' ad grave dampnum &amp; nocumentum om<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nium Ligeorum &amp; Subditorum dicti Domini Regis in augmen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation'
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:51315:5"/>preciorum omnium Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctual' &amp; Proviſion' in Merca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ta praedict' vendit' ac in dicti Domin' Regis nunc &amp; Coronae ſuae Regiae exheredationem ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſtam ac contra fiduc' in ip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſis ut Corpore Corporat' &amp; Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>litic' per Domin' Regem ac Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges hujus Regni Angliae repoſit' prout praedict' Attorn' dict' Dom' Regis nunc Generalis pro eodem Domin' Rege nunc ſuperius re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plicando allegavit, abſque hoc quod praedict' Major &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munitas ac Cives Civitatis <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> à tempore cujus contraria memoria hominum non exiſtit habuer' ſeu habere conſuever' to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luet', rats, ſive denar' ſummas per ipſos Majorem &amp; Civitat' ac Cives Civitat' praedict' ſupe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rius ſuppoſit' fore per praeſat' Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gem ſive Ordination' praedict' aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſs' &amp; in certitudinem reduct' prout placitum ipſorum Majoris &amp; Communitat' ac Civium Civi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat' <hi>London,</hi> praedict' ſuperius rejungendo ſupponitur. Et hoc idem Attorn' General' pro eo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Domin' Rege nunc parat' eſt verificare unde ex quo' iidem Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Libertat', Privileg', &amp; Fran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheſ. praedict' fore de ſeipſis Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pus Corporat' &amp; Politicum ex cauſa praedict' for is fecer' idem At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torn' General'ut prius pro eo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem Domin' Rege nunc pet' Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicium, &amp; quod praedict' Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor &amp; Communitas ac Cives Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tat' <hi>London</hi> praedict', de prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſis convincantur ac de Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bertat', Privileg', &amp; Francheſ. ill'abjudicentur &amp; excluden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tur, &amp;c.</p>
               <p>Et quoad placitum praefat'
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:51315:6"/>Majoris &amp; Communitat' ac Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vium Civitat' praedict' ſuperius rejungendo placitat' quoad reſid' praedict' placiti praefat' Attorn' General'in aſſign' forisfactur' ut prefertur ſuperius replicando placitat' idem' Attorn' dict' Dom' Regis nunc General' proteſtan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>do quod praedict' Prorogatio di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cti Parliamenti per praefat' Dom' Regem fuit pro diverſis neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſar' &amp; urgentibus cauſis bonum &amp; utilitatem dicti Domin' Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gis &amp; Regni ſui concern', &amp; ſecundum veram &amp; indubitat' Prerogativam &amp; poteſtatem di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cti Domin' Regis nunc, Et per eandem. Prorogationem proſecutio publicae Juſtitiae Regni &amp; pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parationis, Anglice <hi>the making proviſions</hi> neceſſar' pro preſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vatian' dict' Domin' Regis &amp; ejus Subditorum Proteſtantium non recepiſſent obſtructionem Ang' <hi>Interruption,</hi> prout per Petitio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nem praedict' per Vota &amp; Suf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fragia praefat' Majoris &amp; Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munit' ac Civium Civitat' prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict' in dicto Communi Concilio aſſemblat' ſic ut prefertur ordinat' falſe &amp; malitioſe allegatur pro placito tamen idem Attorn' Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral' pro eodem Dom' Rege nunc dic' quod placitum praefat' Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joris &amp; Communit' ac Civium Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitat' <hi>London</hi> praedict' ſuperius rejungendo in ea parte placitat' materiaque in eodem content' mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nime ſufficien' in lege exiſtunt ad ipſos Majorem &amp; Communit' ac Cives Civitat' praedict' ad clamand' Libertat', Privileg' &amp; Francheſ. praedict' fore de ſeipſis Corpus Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porat' &amp; Politicum in re facto &amp; nomine per nomen Majoris &amp; Commun' ac Civium Civ' <hi>London</hi> praed', ac per idem nomen placit' &amp; implacit. reſp' &amp; reſponderi ſibi al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>locand'
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:51315:6"/>ſeu adjudicand' manuten', Quodque ipſe idem Attorn' Gener' ad placitum ill' modo &amp; forma, praedict' placitat' pro eodem Dom Reg' nunc neceſſe non habet, nec per Legem terrae tenetur aliquo modo reſpondere. Et hoc idem Attorn' dict' Dom' Regis nunc General' pro eodem Domin' Rege nunc parat' eſt verificare. <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nde pro defectu ſufficien' placiti ipſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum Majoris &amp; Communitat' ac Civium Civitat' praedict' in hac parte idem Attorn' dicti Domin' Regis nunc General' pro eodem Dom' Rege nunc ut prius pet' Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicium, &amp; quod praedict' Major &amp; Communitas ac Cives Civitat' <hi>London</hi> praedict' de premiſſis con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vincantur &amp; de Libertat' Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leg' &amp; Francheſ. ill'abjudicantur &amp; excludantur, &amp;c.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
